我立大地根基时 你在哪里呢
那时 晨星一同歌唱 神的众子也都欢呼
《约伯记》38章4,7节
弟弟
Brother.
母亲
Mother.
是他们领我来到你门前
It was they who led me to your door.
修女教导我们  生命之路有两条
The nuns taught us there were two ways through life —
或是选择自然之道 顺应天性
the way of nature...
或是接受主的恩典 追随指引
and the way of grace.
你必须选择你自己的道路
You have to choose which one you'll follow.
选择跟从主的指引就无法事事顺心
Grace doesn't try to please itself.
承受被轻视 被遗忘 被厌弃
Accepts being slighted, forgotten, disliked.
被侮辱与被伤害
Accepts insults and injuries.
选择顺应天性 取悦自己
Nature only wants to please itself.
感谢主赐予我们食物..
Bless, O Lord, this food —
也取悦他人
Get others to please it too.
感谢你的爱与恩宠..
Your loving and faithful service —
自然之道想要主宰万物
Likes to lord it over them.
保佑这些孩子
Bless these boys.
..让万物顺应天性
To have its own way.
生命中总有苦痛
It finds reasons to be unhappy
但同时 世界又是如此灿烂
when all the world is shining around it...
爱在天地间徜徉
and love is smiling through all things.
她们说 追随主的指引的人
They taught us that no one who loves the way of grace
不会有悲惨的结局
ever comes to a bad end.
我将永远对你虔诚
I will be true to you...
不论发生什么
whatever comes.
哦 天啊！
Oh, God!
我的儿子
My son.
我只想去死
I just wanna die,
去陪他
to be with him.
上帝把他接走了
He's in God's hands now.
上帝从未离开过他
He was in God's hands the whole time.
不是吗？
Wasn't he?
我的希望
My hope.
我的上帝
My God.
我不再畏惧恶的存在
“I shall fear no evil.
*出自《圣经·旧约》诗篇23:4*
不再畏惧了 因为你与我同在
Fear no evil, for you are with me.”
你又能得到什么？
What did you gain?
*出自《圣经·旧约》诗篇22:11*
请不要远离我 因为劫难临近了
“Be not far from me, for trouble is near.”
走吧 我们没事儿了
Go on now. We're all right.
我们没事儿了
We're all right.
谢谢你 谢谢
Thank you. Thank you.
你还惦记着他
You have your memories of him and, uh —
但你得学着坚强
You have to be strong now and —
听我说 痛苦..
I know, uh, the pain will —
痛苦会过去的
It will pass in time, you know.
这也许并不容易
It might seem... hard, my saying that,
但的确是这样
but it's true.
可我不想忘记
I don't want it to.
生活总要继续
Life goes on.
人总有一死
People pass along.
没有什么是永恒不变的
Nothing stays the same.
你还有两个孩子
You still got the other two.
主给予 他也收回
- The Lord gives, and the Lord takes away.
他就是这样
That's the way he is.
他放任那些
He sends flies to wounds
本该由他治愈的伤口于不顾
that he should heal.
我还没来得及告诉他 我有多对不起他
I never got a chance to tell him how sorry I was.
有天晚上
One night he...
他无缘无故的朝自己脸上
punched him — himself in the face
打了一拳
for no reason.
那时我在弹琴 他就坐在我的旁边 我批评了他给我翻谱的方式
He was sittin' next to me at the piano, and I criticized the way he'd turned the pages.
我让他感到很自责
I made him feel shame.
我感到很羞愧
My shame.
可怜的孩子
That poor boy.
你如何来到我的身边
How did you come to me?
以何种面目
In what shape?
何种伪装
What disguise?
我看到了我小时候
I see the child I was.
看到了我的弟弟
I see my brother.
纯真
True.
善良
Kind.
他十九岁时就死了
He died when he was 19.
查查看 这里有问题
Just check this — this one against this.
她想复合
She wants to get back together.
但这段故事已经翻篇了 该说的也都说了
Chapter's closed. Story's been told.
你打算怎么办
What are you gonna do?
看着办吧
Experiment.
嗯 都是关于你的前途
Yeah, it's all about your career.
你还不懂
You don't understand anything.
我觉得自己四处碰壁
I just feel like I'm bumping into walls.
我不知道怎样才算公平
I don't know how to be fair.
世风堕落
The world is gone to the dogs.
人们变得贪得无厌 道德沦丧
People are greedy. They keep getting worse.
过些年
Years later —
他们想让你也变成这样的人
They try to get you into their hands.
会陷入同样的困境
Drifting back into the same swamp.
爸 我不该说那些话
Hey, Dad, I'm sorry I said what I said.
嗯 我每天都会想起他
Yeah. Yeah. I think about him every day.
我不该说那些 对不起
I just shouldn't have said what I did, and I'm sorry.
不 只是 这个时代..
No, it's just, oh... this day.
-你在想什么 -我明白你已经尽力了
- What are you thinking?
- I know you did everything you could.
其中只有两条被顾客驳回了
And only two of those were turned down by the client.
我是如何失去了你？
How did I lose you?
四处徘徊
Wandered?
忘记了你
Forgot you?
回想起
Remember.
噢 你别闹
Oh, no, you don't!
看 你明明挺开心的
See? There, you're happy.
至少有点儿吧
Kind of.
好吧
Okay?
所以 我们仅仅能收回成本
So... we barely broke even.
来找我
Find me.
她是怎么熬过来的
How did she bear it?
母亲
Mother.
我对你不够虔诚么
Was I false to you?
主啊
Lord.
为什么
Why?
你那时在哪里呢
Where were you?
你知道吗
Did you know?
对你来说我们算什么呢
Who are we to you?
回答我吧
Answer me.
我们祈求你的回应
We cry to you.
我的灵魂
My soul.
我的儿子
My son.
倾听我们
Hear us.
我的生命之光啊
Light of my life.
我追寻着你
I search for you.
我的希望
My hope.
我的孩子
My child.
是你让她领我来到你门前
You spoke to me through her.
你在天上与我交流
You spoke with me from the sky.
那些树
The trees.
在我意识到我爱你
Before I knew I loved you,
相信你之前
believed in you.
你何时触动了我的心弦
When did you first touch my heart?
坚持住 快出来了
Hang on. Here we go.
在他的引领下 勇敢地
And manfully to fight under his banner
对抗罪恶 对抗这个世界 对抗邪恶
against sin, the world, and the devil.
有一次我们请中校来吃晚饭 这个小坏蛋一嘴咬人家脚踝上了
We had the commander over for dinner. This little devil bit him right on the ankle.
妈妈
Mama!
我
Me!
犀牛
Rhinoceros.
两条鳄鱼
Two alligator.
Two alligators.
袋鼠
Kangaroo.
跳呀
Jump.
跳呀 跳呀
Jump. Jump.
跳呀
Jump.
啊
Ah!
亲爱的
Sweetheart.
别这样
Shh. Please.
我明白
I know —
不行 不行
No! No.
这是我的
It's mine!
找到我啦
You found me.
在这颗树长成之前 你就长大啦
You'll be grown before that tree is tall.
蓝色 一望无际
Blue. Far.
你
You.
你在害怕吗
Were you afraid?
过来呀
Come here.
过来
- Come here.
到这来 儿子 别站在那儿 那儿是Spencer家的院子 知道了吗
Now, come back here, Son. Stay out of there. That's the Spencers' yard, okay?
你看到这条线了吗
You see this line?
不要越过它 明白吗
Let's not cross it. Do you understand?
明白了吗
Hmm? You understand?
你看到这条线了吗 来 看这儿
You see this line? Look it here. Look here.
好了儿子 回来
Okay, now, come back here, Son. Come on back here.
离那里远点
Stay out of there.
一天早上兔妈妈说到 亲爱的孩子们
“‘Now, my dears,’ said old Mrs. Rabbit one morning,
你们可以到田野或小路上去玩
‘you may go into the fields or down the lane,
但千万不要到McGregor先生的花园里去
but don't go into Mr. McGregor's garden.
你们的爸爸在那里出过事儿
Father had an accident there.’”
那是上帝住的地方
That's where God lives.
晚安
Good night.
我们五年后见
We'll see you in five years.
想吃蚱蜢吗
Want to eat a grasshopper?
我找到了根恐龙的骨头
I found a dinosaur bone!
-噢 -那是块石头吗
- Oh! - Is that a rock?
不是
No.
啊嘿
- Aah! Hey!
孩子们
Boys!
回家啦
Come home!
嘿
Hey!
回家
Come home!
哇噢
- Whoo-hoo-hoo!
你们身上好脏
You're filthy!
感谢主赐予我们食物
Bless this food to our use
感谢你的爱与恩宠
and us to your loving and faithful service,
让我们铭记那些需要帮助的人们
and make us ever mindful of those who are in need.
-阿门 -阿门
- Amen. - Amen.
请把黄油递过来好吗
Will you pass the butter, please?
-请把黄油递过来好吗 先生 -先生
- “Can you pass the butter please, sir?” - Sir.
你今天都干啥了
What'd you do today?
-去上学 -之后呢
- Went to school. - After that?
你在院子里干啥呢
What about the yard?
*纤匍枝是从叶丛的叶腋中发生的无叶细长的伏地枝 其顶端生根并形成莲花状叶丛而形成新植株*
你有没有按我说的把纤匍枝清理好
Did you put the runners in, like I asked?
嗯
Yeah.
是的 先生
Yes, sir.
嗯 但看起来可不像
Well, it didn't look like it.
-嗯 -是的 先生
- Mmm? - Yes, sir.
-Reese先生很喜欢Jack的读书报告 -亲爱的 听听那是什么
- Mr. Reese liked Jack's book report and — - What is that, sweetheart?
想拿他的文章做范文
Wanted him to make a model.
你听过的
You know this.
勃拉姆斯
Brahms.
勃拉姆斯第四交响曲 托斯卡尼尼
-儿子 -先生 怎么了
Son? - Sir
把打火机给我拿过来
Reach me my lighter.
你是不是忘了什么
Haven't you forgotten something?
你爱你的父亲吗
You love your father?
是的 先生
Yes, sir.
他们出发去寻找卡奥 那条岩石巨蟒
“And they went off to look for Kaa, the rock python.
他们发现他正沐浴着午后阳光 蜷在温暖的岩架上
They found him stretched out on a warm ledge in the afternoon sun,
欣赏着自己美丽的新外衣
admiring his beautiful new coat.”
我们三个里你最爱谁
Who do you love the most?
我一样爱
I love you all three the same.
给我们讲个我们记事前的故事吧
Tell us a story from before we can remember.
你爸爸曾经开过一次飞机
Went for a ride in a plane once.
那是他的毕业礼物
It was a graduation present.
母亲
Mother.
教我善良
Make me good.
勇敢
Brave.
哇 啊 啊
Whoa! Aaah! Aaah!
它们摔下来了
They fell.
它们的巢在哪里
Where's the nest?
它们头上有个洞诶
There's a hole in its head.
-你不要碰它 -现在又没了
- You can't hold 'em. - No, not right now.
听我跟你解释
I'll explain to you.
这会发生在任何人身上吗
Can it happen to anyone?
嘘
Shh.
没有人谈论这件事
Nobody talks about it.
请帮助我 不要跟我爸爸顶嘴
Help me not to sass my dad.
请帮助我 不要让狗狗们打架
Help me not to get dogs in fights.
请让我学会感恩自己所拥有的一切
Help me be thankful for everything I got.
让我不再说谎
Help me not to tell lies.
你在注视着我吗
Are you watching me?
我想知道你是谁
I wanna know what you are.
我想看看你所见的
I wanna see what you see.
你们过来啊
- Come here, you!
有趣吗
That funny?
你站在这 轻轻把门关上 重复50次
You're gonna stand there, and you're gonna close this door quietly 50 times.
数出声来
Count it out.
三 四
Three. Four.
五 六
Five. Six.
七 八
Seven. Eight.
你不能只拔它的上面 你得把它连根拔起
Can't just yank off the top. You gotta — gotta get 'em by the root.
你们妈妈很天真
Your mother's naive.
在这个世界上 想要出人头地一定要有强大的意志
It takes fierce will to get ahead in this world.
如果你太善良了 别人就会利用你
If you 're good, people take advantage of you.
那些身居高位的人 你们知道他们是怎么做到的吗
Every one of these top executives, you know how they got where they are?
随波逐流
Floated right down the middle of the river.
别让任何人说你有什么是办不到的
Don't let anyone tell you there's anything you can't do.
向我保证 不要重蹈我的覆辙
Don't do like I did. Promise me that.
我曾想做个伟大的音乐家
I dreamed of being a great musician.
但我半途而废了
I let myself get sidetracked.
如果你想要有所成就 就要像我说的那样
If you're looking for something to happen, that was it.
这就是生活 你得学着接受
That was life. You lived it.
约伯曾经憧憬将巢筑于高处
Job imagined he might build his nest on high,
*出自《约伯记》39章28节 Nest on high比喻一种受上帝庇护的生活*
他相信凭借他正直的品行 上帝就会保护他免遭不幸
that the integrity of his behavior would protect him against misfortune.
约伯的朋友们误认为
And his friends thought, mistakenly,
他一定是偷偷做了什么错事
that the Lord could only have punished him
上帝才会惩罚他
because, secretly, he'd done something wrong.
但并不是这样的
But no.
不幸也会降临在好人身上
Misfortune befalls the good as well.
我们无法避免不幸的降临
We can't protect ourselves against it.
也无法庇护我们的孩子
We can't protect our children.
我们不能对自己说 尽管我们并不开心
We can't say to ourselves, even if I'm not happy,
却能保证孩子们开心
I'm going to make sure they are.
我们现在生活得顺风顺水
We run before the wind.
就认为他会永远保护我们
We think that it will carry us forever.
并不是这样
It will not.
我们如云般消散
We vanish as a cloud.
如秋日的草般枯萎
We wither as the autumn grass
如树被连根拔起
and, like a tree, are rooted up.
那么 是宇宙秩序出错了吗
Is there some fraud in the scheme of the universe?
没有什么是不朽的
Is there nothing which is deathless,
没有什么是不灭的
nothing which does not pass away?
我们不能停滞不前
We cannot stay where we are.
我们必须继续前行
We must journey forth.
我们必须找到那个比财富与命运更重要的东西
We must find that which is greater than fortune or fate.
除此之外 没有什么能够带给我们安宁
Nothing can bring us peace but that.
智慧公正的人难道可以
Is the body of the wise man or the just
免受肉体疼痛
exempt from any pain,
焦虑不安
from any disquietude,
容颜折损
from the deformity that might blight its beauty,
健康不再的折磨吗
from the weakness that might destroy its health?
你相信上帝吗
Do you trust in God?
约伯相信 他曾经离上帝很近
Job, too, was close to the Lord.
那么你的朋友 孩子 你的安全就得到保障了吗
Are your friends and children your security?
这世上没有可以逃离劫难的庇护之所
There is no hiding place in all the world where trouble may not find you.
没有人知道什么时候 悲痛会袭来
No one knows when sorrow might visit his house
就像约伯一样
any more than Job did.
约伯失去一切的那瞬间
The very moment everything was taken away from Job,
他明白是上帝拿走了这一切
he knew it was the Lord who'd taken it away.
他背弃了他的过去
He turned from the passing shows of time.
那段试图追寻永恒的过去
He sought that which is eternal.
难道他只看到上帝之手意味着给予
Does he alone see God's hand who sees that he gives?
却没有看到上帝之手
Or does not also the one see God's hand —
-你就是你要找的人 -同时也意味着收回
- I'm your man. - who sees that he takes away?
难道他只看到上帝将面孔转向他
Or does he alone see God who sees God turn his face towards him?
却不知道同时也是上帝在转向背对他的方向
Does not also he see God who sees God turn his back?
那是我的一个朋友 他名下有镇子的半数房产
That's a friend of mine. He owns half the real estate in town.
Frank Johnson
Frank Johnson.
他做理发师起家
Started out as a barber.
但他成就了番大事业
But he built something big.
现在你可能会认为他是圣三位一体中的第四人
Now you'd think he was the fourth person of the Holy Trinity.
他们对自己的财富闭口不谈
They never talk about their money.
挨饿的都是不该挨饿的人
Wrong people go hungry.
死去的都是不该死的人
Die.
被爱的都是不值得被爱的人
Wrong people get loved.
这个世界充满尔虞我诈
- The world lives by trickery.
如果你想要成功 你就不能太过善良
If you want to succeed, you can't be too good.
嗨 小伙子们 你们今天过得怎么样呀
Hey there, young fellas. How y'all doin' today?
你们想不想吃烧烤
Do all y'all want some barbecue?
一磅牛胸肉怎么卖
How 'bout a pound of brisket?
对不起
I'm sorry.
我能用绳索套你吗
Can I rope you?
如果你想的话
If you want.
不错呀
Good.
你抓到我了
Caught me.
这叫什么
What's that called?
这是个蝴蝶绳结
This is a butterfly.
为什么叫这个名字
Why do they call it that?
因为它可以飘动起来
'Cause it floats.
你打算就这么无所事事地坐着抠肚脐么
You just gonna sit around, picking lint out of your navel?
-你以后要出人头地 -张嘴 让我看看
- You 're gonna have a record. - Open. Let me see.
你的成就会伴随你一生
And it's gonna follow you around for the rest of your life.
如果你搞砸了 你可能连政审都无法通过
If you mess up, you might not be able to get a security clearance.
人们会很好奇
People will ask why.
他们会指责我的教育
They'll point the finger at me.
而一切都取决于你
All but you.
我的儿子啊
My son.
你都除干净了吗
Did you get it all?
是的 先生
Yes, sir.
像这样站着 明白吗 来吧
Stand like this. Right? Okay? Come on.
你要表现出你很害怕 不想打架 不想惹麻烦
You act like you're scared, you're in trouble. You don't wanna fight, you don't want trouble.
然后一看到对方眨眼 你就痛扁他 明白吗
The minute you see him blink, crack him. Okay?
明白吗 来吧 第三回合了
- Okay? Come on. Three-quarters.
防守 你在防守 对吧
Cover. You're gonna cover, right?
来打我 来啊
Okay, hit. Come on.
不错 再用力点 不错 右手打得不错 换左手试试
Nice. Nice. Harder. Nice. That's a good right. Let's see your left.
这是最重要的 懂么
It's the most important thing. Okay?
你这只手出拳 另只手得这么保护自己
You come in this way, you put your guard up.
来打我 来啊 打我
Hit me. Come on. Hit me.
来啊 Jack 来打我
Come on! Come on, Jack, hit me.
打我啊 打我啊 来啊来啊
Hit me. Hit me. Come on. Come on.
来打这里 来啊 儿子
Here it is. Here it is. Hit it. Come on, Son! Come on, Son.
让你出左拳 你在干啥呢
Left — What are you doing?
把自己拍拍干净
Brush yourself off.
左手 别把舌头露出来 会被人打断的
Left. Don't leave your tongue out. You're gonna lose it.
左手 左手
Left. Left.
右手 右手
Right. Right.
左手 用力点
Left. Harder.
用力 用力
Harder. Harder!
来啊 打我 来打我
Come on, hit me. Hit me.
来啊儿子 来打我
Come on, Son, hit.
给我点颜色看看 让我看看你都学到了什么
Give me somethin'. Show me what you got.
来啊 好吧算了
Come on. Go on.
-你准备好了吗
- You ready?
好好吃饭
One meal.
哈
Ah!
滚
Leave the table.
你也想滚吗
You too?
-你打算继续违抗我吗 -没有 先生
- You gonna continue to defy me? - No, sir.
你打断我了
You interrupted me.
我还没说完
I wasn't done yet.
我说完了吗
Am I finished?
没有吗
No?
-没有 -那我真是谢谢你了 殿下
- No. - Thank you, Your Majesty.
编造故事
Makes up stories.
乱定规矩
Original words.
他说不要把胳膊架在桌子上
He says don't put your elbows on the table.
你们准备好了吗
You ready?
他自己却这么做
He does.
辱骂别人
Insults people.
不懂得关心
Doesn't care.
我还记得你出生的时候
I remember when you were born.
他们不让我回家
They wouldn't let me come home.
他们说海军长官必须出席铺龙骨仪式
The navy said an officer must be present for the laying of the keel, but...
*船只的四大仪式
铺龙骨KeelLaying 下水Launching 试航Commissioning 退役Decommisioning*
但不必出席下水仪式
not at the launching.
我曾认为我父亲的付出是理所当然的
I took my father for granted.
一个和善的男人
A sweet man.
我却认为他软弱
I thought he was weak.
一个焊接工 机械师
A welder. Machinist.
他已经尽力了
He did what he could.
他还推销房地产 保险
Real estate. Insurance.
他一天工作12个小时 一周工作6天
He worked 12 hours a day, six days a week.
四十年的辛勤工作 你知道他换来了什么吗
Forty years he served them. You know what he got for it?
一只腕表
A wristwatch.
有人开车碾过了他 任他倒在地上 自己跑了
Somebody ran him over and left him in the street.
任他死在了路上
Left him in the street to die.
很长一段时间 我只有一条长裤
For years I had one pair of pants.
一条绿色的长裤
Same green pants.
当我的母亲把它洗了时 我只能穿着短裤跑来跑去
Had to run around in my shorts while my mother washed 'em.
你不知道为一个你瞧不上的人工作会是什么样子
You have no idea what it's like working for men you don't respect.
这让你觉得自己一文不值
It makes you less than a man.
下个单词是volcano
Next word is “volcano.”
下个单词是socket
Next word is “socket.”
现在请把你们的答案交换一下 给对方判个分
Please pass your answers to each other. We're gonna grade each other's papers now.
不要捣乱呀
No interruptions, please.
快点 把铅笔拿出来
Come on. Get your pencil out.
当原木进入造纸厂后..
After the logs go to the paper mill...
你叫什么名字
What is your name?
Jack
Jack.
谁给你起的名字
Who gave you this name?
我的教父给我起的
My sponsors in baptism,
在我受洗后 我成为一名基督徒
where I was made a member of Christ,
上帝的子女
a child of God,
天国的一个继承者
an i-in-inheritor of the kingdom of heaven.
你对邻人的责任是什么
What is thy duty toward thy neighbor?
爱邻人像爱自己一样
My duty towards my neighbor is to love him as myself.
我见过一只三条腿的狗
- Saw a three-legged dog.
它到处跑啊
Ran around...
就像它并没什么不同
like nothin' was the matter.
来这儿啊
Come here!
不要 不要
No, no, no, no!
我鞋上全是泥了
I'm all muddy!
啊
Aaah!
啊 啊
Aaah! Aaah!
亲爱的
Sweetheart!
Tyler 亲爱的
Tyler! Sweetheart!
亲爱的 你醒醒啊
Honey? Honey?
有人救救他吗 求你了
Please, somebody —
他是坏人吗
Was he bad?
这说起来有点难为情
It's sort of embarrassing.
你也会死吗
Will you die too?
你还没那么老呢 妈妈
You're not that old yet, Mom.
啊
- Aaah!
你在哪
Where were you?
你就这样让一个男孩死了
You let a boy die.
任由一切发生
You 'll let anything happen.
韦科市DDT
我看不到啦 我看不到啦
I can't see! I can't see!
我为什么要做个好人
Why should I be good...
如果你都不是
if you aren't?
谢谢
Thank you.
种的太近了
Close.
注意边缘
Edges.
这里又太空了
Bare.
把那个放下
Put that down.
你知道这里为什么是秃的吗
Why's this bare here? Hmm?
-树底下不长草 -Kimball家的树下就长
- Grass won't grown under the trees. - Does at the Kimballs'.
-他们有园丁 -他们有钱
- They have a yardman. - They have money.
当然虽说是他继承来的吧
Course, he inherited it.
在你干完活之前 我不想再听到你废话了
I don't wanna hear one more word out of you, not till this is finished.
嗯
Hmm?
你把它们种的太近了
You're croppin' that too close.
以至于你得经常浇灌它们
Gonna have to keep that watered.
托斯卡尼尼曾经录制一首曲子 录了65遍
Toscanini once recorded a piece 65 times.
你知道当他终于完成后 他说了什么吗
You know what he said when he finished?
还能更好
It could be better.
你想想吧
Think about it.
你的父亲有27项专利
Twenty-seven patents your father has.
专利意味着占有 对创意的占有
That means ownership. Ownership of ideas.
你必须得牢牢攥住它们
You gotta sew 'em up.
-你得抓住要害 原谅我说得粗俗 -我们下次再争取吧
- Get 'em by the nuts, if you 'll pardon my French. - We'll get 'em next time.
你可以变得富有
You can be rich.
你能做你想做的
You make yourself what you are.
你能掌握自己的命运
You have control of your own destiny.
千万不要说 我不能
Can't say “I can't.”
应该说 我有了些麻烦
You say, “I'm having trouble.
我还没有被击败呢
I'm not done yet.”
千万不要说 我不能
You can't say “I can't.”
他为什么要伤害我们
Why does he hurt us,
我们的父亲
our father?
-来啊 Dix -好耶 我接到了
Come on, Dix! Come on! Oh, yeah. Get it! Get it!
走你
Go!
给你的父亲一个吻
Give your father a kiss.
他骗人
He lies.
-虚伪 -你能为我做件事吗
- Pretends. - Can you do something for me?
你能答应听我的话 不要问为什么 去做就是了
You promise you'll do it without having to ask what it is?
就是相信你父亲让你做的一定是对的
Just have the confidence that what your father asks of you is right?
好的 先生
Yes, sir.
未来半个小时 除非有什么特别紧要的事情 你能闭上你的嘴吗
For the next half hour, will you not speak unless you have something important to say?
你今天都做什么啦 这位打扮得这么精致的小朋友
What'd you do today, my fine-feathered friend?
坐在椅子靠前的部分
Sit on the front two inches of your chair.
这种姿势更好
Better for your posture.
我在报纸上读到的
I read that in the paper.
这个是你从Ledbetter女士那里买的吗
Did you actually buy this from Mr. Ledbetter?
-不要解释 就点头 是或否
- Don't explain. Just nod, yes or no.
别出声音
Be quiet.
你说什么
What did you say?
求你了
Please.
-别碰他 -你给我过来
- Leave him alone! - Come here!
亲爱的
Honey!
别碰他
- Leave him alone!
过来 你们滚开 你过来
Come here! Get back. Come here.
滚出去
Get out there!
你让我的孩子违抗我
You turned my own kids against me.
你让我做的一切都失去意义
You undermine everything I do.
你喜欢这样吗
How do you like it?
别动了
Stop it!
别动
Stop.
Stop it.
别动
Stop.
-你练吉他了吗 -练了 先生
- Did you practice your guitar? - Yes, sir.
你在这干什么呢
What are you doing out here...
还下着小雨呢
in the rain?
嗯
Well...
他很狠心
He's pitiless.
就像所有意志脆弱的人一样 他内心充满了苛责
Like all weak spirits, he's just full of criticisms
和矛盾
and... contrariness.
他拒绝认清现实
He just refuses to see who he really is.
他就像是双面人 你知道的 其中一面他只是想
He's two people, you know. He just wants to...
做个非常非常和善的人
be very, very kind one half of himself,
另一面却像一个守财奴一样刻薄吝啬
and the other half is as mean as a miser.
他甚至不会送你一颗鸡蛋
He wouldn't give you an egg.
他是在嫉妒孩子们
He's jealous of the boys.
当人们有了孩子之后 事情变得越来越糟
Things often get worse and worse when people have children.
这很常见
It's well-known.
爱情逝去 或者开始逝去
Love fades, or, you know, the beginning of it fades,
激情褪去 人们开始厌烦彼此的种种
the passion goes, and people start to dislike each other's habits and that,
你必须得承认这些
and you have to admit —
如果我早知道这些 我肯定会退缩
Well, if I knew then what I know now, I'd have get my legs in a jog.
谁需要这些孩子
Who needs all them boys?
你的弟弟们 他们从来没有让我省心
Your brothers, they never really got off to any kind of a start at all.
对于我来说他们还像十岁小孩一样
They still come to me for a ten.
小心
Be careful.
他三年没上交过所得税申请表了
He hasn't filed an income tax return in three years.
我担心他会失业
I'm afraid he'll lose his job.
在他手下干活实在太苦了
Works the men under him too hard.
没有人喜欢他
Nobody likes him.
倒不是说他是个冷酷自私的人 只是
It isn't that he's a cold or selfish man, but...
他总能让别人与他为敌
He turns people against him.
他故意冒犯别人
He offends them almost on purpose.
尽管他为这个家真的做了很多
He's a good provider though.
他勤奋工作
He works hard.
我也可以去找份工作
I could get a job.
但他不想我这样
He doesn't want me to though.
我考虑过了
I've thought about it.
我现在还会速记打字
I still know shorthand.
我在Benedict先生那里工作的时候
When I worked at Benedict's.
我一分钟能打一百词
I can type a hundred words a minute.
在这
Right here!
那时我还没有结婚
Before we got married.
我不知道我现在还能做些什么
I don't know what I could do now...
有了这三个孩子后
with three boys.
你以前很喜欢安静的
You used to love science.
喜欢结交自由自在的人
Wanted to meet free people.
我曾经以为我永远不会结婚
I thought I'd' never marry.
也不会有人爱我
And no one would love me.
我错了
I was wrong.
当男孩们出生之后
When those boys were born...
我的生活才真正开始
my life began.
你要离开我们了吗
Are you gonna leave us?
你为什么这么问
Why do you ask that?
我不知道
I don't know.
没有为什么
Just 'cause.
啊
- Whoa.
不
- No!
我爱你啊
I love you.
抓住他
Get him!
- Get him!
噢
Oh-ho-ho!
你知道我把你当兄弟
You know you're like a brother to me.
我就跟你直说了
I want to be square with you.
你不能依赖你的朋友 但家人不一样
You can't rely on your friends to, but family...
你强迫他们爱你 不管他们怎么想的
You force them to love you whether they like it or not.
我忍你多久了 Ray
How long I been putting up with you, Ray?
你来我家蹭吃蹭喝了多少年了
How many years you been coming here, moochin' off my family?
你这么在意你姐姐 却一点忙都帮不上
Not lifting a hand to help out your sister you're so concerned about.
嗯 我是你的仆人吗
Hmm? Am I your servant?
我已经很体谅你的窘况了
I have great sympathy for your nervous condition.
我理解你工作不易
I understand how hard it is for you to keep at a job.
妻子跑了 房车被烧毁了
Wife ran off, your trailer burned down.
你可怜的妈妈还从灰烬里把锅碗瓢盆捡出来
And your poor mother, pulling them pots and pans from the ashes,
还想把它们擦亮
trying to shine 'em up.
你以为你举起块大石头就能影响我的孩子们吗
You think you can pick up a big rock and impress my boys?
你知道6为什么不开心吗
Why was six upset?
嗯？
Hmm?
因为7吃了9
'Cause seven ate nine.
*谐音梗 eight与ate发音接近*
啊
Ah!
给你
Here.
爸爸去哪了
Where's Dad?
他出差了
He's gone on a trip.
哇哦
Whoo!
- Whoo!
抓住她 抓住她
Get her! Get her!
抓住她
Get her!
互相帮助
- Help each other.
不要摔门
Do not slam that screen door!
等等
Wait!
爱所有人
Love everyone.
爱每一片叶子
Every leaf.
爱每一缕光
Every ray of light.
宽恕
Forgive.
这是我的房子
This is my house!
是我让你们住 你们才能住在这
You're allowed to live here!
别挡着我的道
Get out of my way!
闭嘴
Shut up!
我接到啦 接到啦
I got it, I got it, I got it!
你有很多朋友吗
Do you have a lot of friends?
我认识些朋友
I know some guys.
你爸爸在哪
Where's your daddy?
你为什么不给我把树枝剪下来
Why don't you cut me a switch.
*俗语 指成人让小孩子从树上剪树枝 以供他抽打使用*
那样再好不过了吧
Wouldn't that be nice?
所有东西都由糖果做成 我们都能随心所欲
Everything's made of candy, and we all get our way.
每个人都 都像只青蛙一样蹦来蹦去
And everybody's just — everybody's just hoppin' around like frogs.
整个世界就像个青蛙池
The whole world a frog pond.
你就在这屋子里和狗待着吧 你没有喂它水
Grew up in this house with that dog. You didn't give him water.
是什么让你的手没有长成鳍
What stops your hands from turning into fins?
你琢磨琢磨吧
Think about it.
什么也没有
Nothin'.
嗯？
Huh?
孩子们 把窗户关上
- Boys, close the windows!
主啊 这就是星期一的一场遭遇
Lord, it was just a-ridin' on Monday.
龙卷风袭来的一段经历
Just a-ridin'.
一些人有所得 一些人有所失
A-gettin' some and a-missin' some.
Bud只是其中之一
And Bud was just one of the ones.
一幢房子被卷起 横贯街道
There was a house picked up, took across the street.
然后又在风里穿行了一里路 里面的碗碟却整整齐齐
Then picked up and took a mile down the road, and there wasn't a dish out of place.
这是怎么做到的
How does it do it?
雨倾泻而下 一位女士躲在门廊上
Rain just pourin'. One lady hid on the porch.
他藏在车里
He hid in his car.
雨下得这么大 他什么都看不到
Raining so hard, he couldn't even see.
一辆车被撞毁 下一辆却完好无损
One car smashed, the next car wouldn't have a scratch.
真可怜
Pitiful.
市中心都毁了
Downtown's gone.
114人死了
114 dead.
小心
Look out!
想象下它要亲你
- Think he wants a kiss.
砰砰 砰砰
- Boom, boom, boom! Boom, boom!
-小心 -小心
- Watch out! - Watch out!
跑
Go!
-我们需要石头 -给你
- Yeah, we need rocks. We need rocks. - Here you go.
去拿点小石头来
- Go get rocks!
-去拿石头 -停下来 停下来
- Get a rock! - Stop! Stop, stop, stop.
让我们看看它能不能爬过去
- See if it'll go over this thing.
唔
Ew!
停下来 别动别动
Stop, stop. Don't, don't.
-哇 -来这儿啊
- Whoa! - Go! Come over here!
-他要过来了 -小心小心
- He's gonna come — - Watch out, watch out!
不
No.
啊
Aaah!
救救我
Help me!
救命呀
Help!
噢
Oh!
-哇 -这不是我们的东西
- Whoa! - It's not ours.
-嗯 这不是我们的 -谁在乎呢 你打算告密吗
- Yeah, that's not ours. - Who cares? You gonna tell?
你不主动索取 就永远无法得到
You don't take something, you're not gonna get it.
只有傻子才会被抓到
Only stupid people get caught.
你觉得我很傻吗
Think I'm stupid?
你害怕了
You afraid?
-一 -二
- One! - Two!
这个雷达显示它在你嘴里
This radar says it's in your mouth.
让我看看
Let me see.
张嘴
Open your mouth.
我们得把它留给Dexter
Gonna save him for Dexter.
-它日落之前不会松口的 -我们快去抓住它
- It won't let go till sunset. - Then let's get him.
来啊Dexter 我们为你准备了个惊喜
Come here, Dexter. I got a surprise for you.
-让它站起来 站起来 -让鳖咬住它
- Get him up. Get him up. - Get it on him.
-就这儿 -我们让它咬耳朵尖的部分
- Right there. - Let's put it right on the end of his ear.
这里很好下嘴
It'd fit right there.
-咬这儿 -别了吧
- Right there. - No.
嘿 Steve
Hey, Steve!
我认为他们不在家
I don't think they're home.
谁在乎呢
Who cares?
这些是属于所有人的
They belong to everybody.
不
No.
来吧 我们来吧
Come on. Let's do it.
我们把它打碎吧
I say let's bust it.
耶
Yeah!
-扔的不错 -耶
- That's a good one. - Yeah.
找到只青蛙
- Found a frog.
-我们把它放在小火箭上发射出去吧 -它要跑了
- Let's go set it off on a skyrocket. - He's getting away!
后退 后退
Get back! Get back!
哇
Whoa!
它到月亮上去了吗
Did it go to the moon?
它去哪了
Where is he?
它在那儿呢
Here he is.
这只是个实验
It was an experiment!
骗子
Liar.
再别做这种事了
Never do it again.
能答应我吗
Promise?
你准备告诉爸爸吗
You gonna tell Dad?
大人们只是在吓唬你
They're just trying to scare you.
让你保持无知
Keep you ignorant.
你要知道
Things you got to learn.
在我们看到事物之前怎么可能认识它呢
How can we know stuff till we look?
他们不让你做的事
They say you can't try stuff?
他们自己却做
They do.
你还怕什么
What do you need to be afraid of?
你在害怕
You afraid.
我看出来了
I see it.
在这儿 在这儿
Right here! Right here!
我不能跟你说
I can't talk to you.
你别看着我
Don't look at me.
我怎么了
What have I started?
我都做了什么
What have I done?
把它插到这
Stick it in there.
我相信你
I trust you.
砰
Buzz!
-你累了 -才没有
- You tired? - No.
我从来不会累
I never get tired.
-你今早就很累啊 -不 那是我装的
- Did this morning. - No, I was just pretending.
-你说我是骗子吗 -不
- Gonna call me a liar? - No.
我不想打架
I don't want to fight.
害怕了
Afraid to?
不 我就是不想
No, I just don't wanna.
如果我说你害怕了 你会叫我骗子吗
If I was to say you're scared, would you call me a liar?
不会
No.
那你就是害怕了 对吧
Then you're scared, aren't you?
哈哈
Ha-ha!
别闹了
Quit it.
能原谅我吗
Forgive me?
你最好收回你的话
Take it back!
你干什么呢
What did you do?
回答我
Answer me.
下一个词是propel
Next word is “propel.”
这些词我们周二刚复习过 我很高兴看到大部分同学都写对了
These are words we went over Tuesday, so I'm happy to see most of you getting them right.
你的能力不止于此
You can do better than what you've been doing.
你能告诉我关于木星的一些知识点吗
Can you tell me something about Jupiter?
你看上去在害怕什么
You seem afraid of something.
他甚至无法画完一幅画
He wouldn't even complete his painting.
他害怕会画错
He was afraid it might be wrong.
我跟他说这没什么对错
I told him it can't be wrong.
他是个好男孩
He's a good boy.
他就是看上去缺乏自信
He just seems to lack confidence.
他并没有专心听我的课
He doesn't seem to hear my instructions.
愣神
Stares.
比如那篇关于埃及的报告 他是从世界百科全书上照抄的
Like on his Egypt report, he copped it right out of the World Book.
-他抄袭了 -是的
- He cheated? - He cheated.
他破坏课堂秩序
He disrupts the entire class.
他掌握不了评论文章的写法
He cannot handle criticism.
我们一直在引导他
We're constantly getting on him all the time.
我把一切都给了你
I give you everything I got!
在我小时候还在南奥斯汀时
When I was growing up in South Austin,
我爸爸希望我能把所有事都做得尽善尽美
my dad wanted everything perfect.
如果我做得有瑕疵 他就会打我的屁股
If I didn't do it perfect, he'd wear my little butt out.
这些年来 我对我的运动员们也经常这样要求
And I pretty much done that over the years with my athletes.
但对学生就没必要这样
Not necessarily the students.
但对屁股挨板子的恐惧可能会有奇妙的作用
But that fear of that board on their little butt can do wonders.
最令我惊讶的是 当我告诉他我要找家长开会时
What really surprised me, when I told him I was gonna have this conference with you,
他脸一下子红了
he went totally pink.
我总是在做蠢事
I always do stupid things.
我想回到小时候多好啊
I want to be little again.
“Coecha makeecha” 那个词语
“Coecha makeecha.” The words.
什么词语
What words?
那个让人们不再刻薄的词语
The words that'll stop people from being mean.
我再也听不到它了
I'll never find it again.
听啊
Listen.
我再也不信这种事情了
I don't believe in that stuff anymore.
过来
Come here.
不
No!
我不会做你让我做的任何事的
I'm not gonna do everything you tell me to.
我想做什么就做什么
I'm gonna do what I want.
你知道什么呢 你就这样让他骑在你头上
What do you know? You let him run all over you.
我怎么才能回到过去
How do I get back...
他们在哪
where they are?
-儿子你好吗 -挺好
- How are you, Son? - Good.
这个挺重的 你得两只手拎着
This one's heavy. You're gonna need two hands for that one.
看看这个
Look at this.
注意啦 你知道这个是什么吗
Careful now. You know what that — You know what —
-中文吗 -对啦 是中文
- Chinese? - That's Chinese.
很不错嘛 是中文
That's very good. Yes, it is.
你父亲我环游世界 一路到了中国
Your father went all around the world, all the way to China.
那是泛美航空 你父亲我坐的航班
That's Pan Am airlines. That's what your father flew on.
整个卫生间都是不锈钢做的 连洗手池都是
The entire bathrooms are stainless steel, even the washbasin.
我相信这笔生意进展的不错
I feel confident the deal's going through.
如果他们要放弃这笔生意 让他们去死好了
If not, they can forget it. I'll tell them all to go to hell.
-那是从德国带回来的 -这个怎么用啊
- That's from Germany. - How do you use them?
看到了吗
See that?
儿子 把那个放下来
Put that down, Son.
能让Gayler过来玩吗
Can Gayler come over?
有你的家人陪你还不够吗
Is your family not good enough for you?
你知道我在你出生时做了什么吗
You know what I did when you were born?
我跑出去在草坪上手舞足蹈
I went out and I danced on the lawn.
兴奋地掏出我的配枪射击
Shot off my service revolver.
你看看你现在 望着窗户愣神 浪费时间
See you wasting your time staring out the window.
那能让你得到什么
Where's that gonna get you?
我为你牺牲了很多
I make sacrifices for you.
请用你的所作所为来珍惜我的付出
Honor those sacrifices by what you do.
-你刚才说啥 -“抱歉 你刚才说了什么”
- What? - Excuse me?
“抱歉 你刚才说了什么 先生”
Excuse me, sir?
这么说 “抱歉 你刚才说了什么”
Say it. “Excuse me.”
抱歉 你刚才说了什么
Excuse me.
-“先生” -先生
- “Sir.” - Sir.
好好听着 儿子 你应该学些东西
Just listen, Son. You might actually learn something.
-弟弟在哪呢 -这不是你现在应该关心的
- Where's my brother? - That's not important right now, is it?
好吧
Okay.
你看看这个
You see this?
你知道我为什么留着它吗
You know why I keep that?
这是我自己公司的公章
It's the official seal of my own company.
我自己创办的公司
The one I formed.
直到我在中国喝了未杀菌的啤酒后得了肝炎
Till I got hepatitis from drinking unpasteurized beer in China.
把那根棍子放下 儿子
Put the stick down, Son.
我尽我所能保护你
I protected you as best I can,
但我没有机会接受教育
but I didn't get an education.
而你有
You will.
但我可以补偿自己
But I can redeem myself.
你就是我的自由
You're my freedom.
这就是你跟我说的吗
Is that what you're telling me?
好吧 也许你应该在广告里说的直接一些
Well, maybe you ought to get your ad straight.
你想想吧 孩子们
You think? Boys!
你没必要这么生气 你..
You don't have to leave in a huff. You can —
-你刚才说什么呢 孩子们我们走了 -我说你没必要这么生气
- Did you say something? Boys, let's go. - You don't have to leave in a huff.
我告你吧 如果我有世界上所有的钱..
I tell you what. If I had all the money in the world —
你这样的骗人精我见多了
I've heard about enough from clip artists like you.
放松点
Relax.
什么
What?
希望不要像上次等那么久
Hope it's not going to take as long as last time.
做的筋道点
Al dente.
这是主观观点 你知道有什么区别吗
Subjective point of view. You know the difference?
主观意味着是你自己的见解 不能被他人证明
Subjective means it comes from your mind. Can't be proven by other people.
嗯
- Mmm.
唔
Oop.
-很高兴又见到你 -嗯
- Good to see you again. - Okay.
我们走吧 孩子们
Let's go, boys.
快点
Come on.
你在害怕吗 再游远点
You afraid? Go out further.
那是噬鱼蛇吗
Is that a water moccasin?
你只看到了脑袋吗
You see a head, and that's all?
那是海龟
That's a turtle.
有些事情你做不到 我也同样如此
There are things you can't do. Well, there are things I can't do either.
你别叫我爸爸 叫我父亲
You are not to call me Dad. You will call me Father.
-但.. -别打断我
- But — - Don't interrupt!
-但你自己.. -别打岔
- But you did. - Don't interrupt!
这是你的家 你随时可以让我滚
It's your house. You can kick me out whenever you want to.
你想要杀了我
You'd like to kill me.
他为什么会出生
Why was he born?
求你了 上帝 杀了他
Please, God, kill him.
让他去死
Let him die.
让他远离我的生活
Get him out of here.
她只爱我一个
She only loves me!
主啊 求你保佑你的孩子 赐予他恩典
Defend, O Lord, this, thy child, with thy heavenly grace,
保佑他永受圣恩
that he may continue thine forever...
日渐成长 圣灵赐福
and daily increase in thy holy spirit more and more
直至他来到你永恒的王国
until he come unto thy everlasting kingdom.
阿门
Amen.
看我的
See somethin'.
把你手指放过来
Put your finger over it.
像这样
Like that.
来吧
Come on.
我无法做我想做的
What I want to do I can't do.
我做的都是我讨厌的
I do what I hate.
给你
Here.
你想的话就打我吧
You can hit me if you want.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你是我的弟弟
You're my brother.
你想向我呈现什么
What is it you showed me?
我不知该怎么称呼
I didn't know how to name you then...
但我知道那是你
but I see it was you.
你总是在呼唤我
Always you were calling me.
你的妈妈和我都没有机会读完大学
We never got to finish college, your mother and I.
让你有更好的教育机会对我们很重要
But it's important to us that we get you the best education
我们可以给你提供这个机会
we can possibly provide.
所以我们决定 为了你好
So we've decided that it's in your best interest
我们要把你送去学校
that we send you away to school.
只有100英里远
Now, it's only a hundred miles away.
我们周末和假期还是能去看你
We'll still be able to see you on weekends and vacations.
我跟那里的人说过了 他们都知道你是个好男孩了
I've talked to the people there. They know you're a good boy.
我想这会是最好的选择
I think this will be for the best.
既然你难以和你的父亲
You've been having such trouble with your father.
你的同学相处
And with your classmates at school.
我们没能尽到家长的责任
We haven't been good parents,
不然不会给你造成这么大的压力
or you wouldn't be under all this tension.
我们应该做个更好的榜样
We should have set a better example.
我会很想你的
I will miss you very much.
我希望有人爱我 因为我很棒
I wanted to be loved because I was great.
是个顶天立地的男儿
A big man.
但我什么都不是
I'm nothin'.
看看我们身边的美好
Look at the glory around us.
树木与鸟儿
Trees and birds.
我活在羞愧中
I lived in shame.
我没有珍惜这一切 忽视了身边的美好
I dishonored it all and didn't notice the glory.
我是个愚蠢的人
I'm a foolish man.
他们要关闭工厂
They're closing the plant.
他们让我选择
They gave me a choice.
要么失业
No job...
要么换个没人乐意做的岗位
or transfer to a job nobody wants.
父亲
Father.
我从来没有懈怠过一天的工作
I never missed a day of work.
母亲
Mother.
我每个星期日都去捐税
I tithed every Sunday.
*特指缴纳给教会的捐款*
你们永远是我心中的羁绊
Always you wrestle inside me.
永远都是
Always you will.
你知道吗 Jack 我想让你做的
You know, Jack, all I ever wanted for you was...
无非是想让你变得强大
to make you strong and...
能够掌握自己命运
grow up and be your own boss.
也许我对你过于苛责了
Maybe I've been tough on you.
我并不为此感到自豪
I'm not proud of that.
我和你一样糟糕
I'm as bad as you are.
相比于妈妈 我更像你
I'm more like you than her.
你们仨是我人生唯一的成就 除此之外我一无所有
You boys are about all I've done in life. Otherwise I've drawn a zilch.
你是我的一切 我想要的一切
You're all I have. You're all I wanna have.
我亲爱的儿子
My sweet boy.
你就打算在那像个木头一样站着么
You just gonna stand there like a bump on a log?
放里面
Go on.
幸福的唯一方式就是去爱
The only way to be happy is to love.
只有去爱
Unless you love...
你的生命才不会一晃而过
your life will flash by.
请善待他们
Do good to them.
奇迹
Wonder.
希望
Hope.
弟弟
Brother.
养育我们
Keep us.
指引我们
Guide us...
直到时间的尽头
till the end of time.
跟着我
Follow me.
♪阿门♪
♪ Amen ♪
我把儿子交付给你
I give you my son.
♪阿门♪
♪ Amen ♪